# DAVID GIBBONS WEB DEVELOPER

## ■ gibbonsdav@gmail.com

- www.david-gibbons.com/
- **\** 702.245.5372
- **♀** 8441 Mulcahy Ave; Las Vegas, NV 89145
- in david-gibbons-lv/
- gibbonsdav

Graduate of Punchcode, focused on technologies such as HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Express, REST APIS, Socket.io, Bootstrap, and MongoDB.

Proficient in version control systems with experience using Git, Github, and Bitbucket. Experience in task management systems such as Trello, tracking issues in Jira, and Kanban style project management. Experience in Agile and Scrum practices. Member of Las Vegas Developer's Group and Agile NV. Formerly a real estate professional with Realty One Group.

## **Skills**

# FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

Html5

CSS3

Javascript

React

Redux

#### **BACK END DEVELOPMENT**

Express

Socket.io

MySQL

Node.js

MongoDB

....

#### **OTHER SKILLS**

Github

Customer Relations

Agile

**Process Management** 

# **Projects**

#### YouTube Sharing App

Created an app along with group members that allows a pair of users to select and view a YouTube video together in a private room. The users' screens sync up and support a number of interactive features such as pausing, fast-forwarding, or rewinding. The application also includes a chat bar so the users can actively discuss the video they are watching. Completed in 3 weeks with a skeleton team as our capstone project.

#### Volunteer Developer at TheCrag.com

July 2020 to Current

Volunteer developer working with the full-time development team. Collaborating via trello board to address current issues and develop future features. Worked on issues ranging from risk management to technical debt, while exploring features of personal interest as well. Gained experience setting up development environment utilizing docker containers and dealt with legacy systems originally written in Perl.

# **Employment**

## Realty One Group

Las Vegas, NV 2013 to 2020

Residential Realtor

- Utilized CRM software to analyze incoming client data, automate follow-up procedures, and increase sales.
- Managed the lifecyle of real estate transactions with Kanban style organization planned from a project's inception through to the closing transaction and subsequent follow-ups.
- Leveraged soft skills to generate new leads, manage customer expectations, and negotiate transactions by reaching a group consensus.

# Skybridge Education

Las Vegas, NV(remote position)

2011 to 2012

Data Entry

- Developed educational software for math and civics for MacMillan/McGraw-Hill.
- Integrated content from textbook authors into various formats.
- Systematically classified and tagged content for coherent grouping and improved search functionality.

# The Nichols Company Commercial Real Estate Broker

Charlotte, NC 2004 to 2009

- Represented real estate developers pursuing land for infill redevelopments in Charlotte's center city.
- Represented property owners in land disposition in Uptown Charlotte.
- Conducted retail tenant representation for many types of businesses.
- Marketed office, retail, land, and industrial properties for sale and for lease.
- Performed financial analysis of income properties and studied rezoning procedures.

## **Education**

#### Punchcode

Jan. 2020 to Current

Web Development 2020

A 12 week immersive in person course in Full-Stack Web Development

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Bachelor's Degree Economics 2004

Aug. 2000 to May 2004

### **Activities**

Avid rock climber for over 20 years including visits to many parts of the US and many countries around the world.